<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Tetrahedrons &amp; Terminals</title><link href="http://dwgill.github.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://dwgill.github.com/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://dwgill.github.com/</id><updated>2017-04-20T12:00:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>First rpg post</title><link href="http://dwgill.github.com/my-first-rpg-post.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-20T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-04-20T12:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Gill</name></author><id>tag:dwgill.github.com,2017-04-20:/my-first-rpg-post.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The first rpg post on the site&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This is a dummy post supposed to serve as the first item in the 'rpg'
category on the site.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="rpg"></category><category term="dnd"></category></entry><entry><title>This Blog Runs on Pelican</title><link href="http://dwgill.github.com/this-blog-runs-on-pelican.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-20T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-04-20T12:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Gill</name></author><id>tag:dwgill.github.com,2017-04-20:/this-blog-runs-on-pelican.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A detailed breakdown of how this blog is coded &amp;amp; built&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This blog is built using the &lt;a href="https://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; static site generator,
written in &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Python_(programming_language)"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;, and utilizes the &lt;a href="https://github.com/alexandrevicenzi/Flex"&gt;Flex&lt;/a&gt; pelican theme.
I'm actually writing this post as I set up the site for the first time,
partially so that I can document everything for myself, and hopefully
because it will be of some use for anyone else who finds him-or-herself
dealing with this in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pelican is a static site generator, which means basically that allows me
to write content for this blog in simple &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown"&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; files,
and uses those files to generate the individual pages of this website.
It takes my markdown files as input, and outputs the entire body of
html files that comprise this website. I can then take those html
files and host them anywhere I like—on my own server, or on 
&lt;a href="https://pages.github.com/"&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pelican has a pretty simple quickstart process, which can be found
&lt;a href="http://docs.getpelican.com/en/stable/install.html"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Altogether my first steps looked like the
following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;cd &amp;lt;project_dir&amp;gt;
virtualenv .venv
source .venv/bin/activate
pip install pelican markdown
pelican-quickstart
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;That was straightforward enough (the living hell of trying to figure)
out a name for this blog notwithstanding), but the next step was
bettering the look of the site. The default look of Pelican is not the
greatest. For example, &lt;a href="https://blog.getpelican.com/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; is the official Pelican
website at the time of this writing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="getpelican.com circa 2017" src="http://dwgill.github.com/images/code/getpelican-site-2017-04-20.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not my style, and not responsive besides. I looked through the themes
available on &lt;a href="http://www.pelicanthemes.com/"&gt;pelicanthemes.com&lt;/a&gt; and found &lt;a href="https://github.com/alexandrevicenzi/Flex"&gt;Flex&lt;/a&gt; to be to my
taste while not complicating things too much up front. Pelican seems to
half-expect you to install themes via the &lt;code&gt;pelican-themes&lt;/code&gt; program
which is installed alongside Pelican, but that seems to operate by
installing themes on a system wide basis and I preferred to have the
project self-contained in my Git repo as much as possible. I ended up
going with putting the Flex's git repo in a git
&lt;a href="https://git-scm.com/docs/git-submodule"&gt;submodule&lt;/a&gt; of my project repository. An introduction to 
Git is beyond the purview of this article (I got myself familiar with it 
with the &lt;a href="https://www.codeschool.com/courses/git-real"&gt;Code School course&lt;/a&gt;, personally), but
&lt;a href="https://git-scm.com/docs/git-submodule"&gt;Git submodules&lt;/a&gt; aren't all that common, and as that's
what I ended up going with I figured I might detail what I did. At the
very least, it will be useful when I come back in a while wondering how
the devil you're supposed to handle a Git submodule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I added the flex repo to my project like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;mkdir themes
git submodule add https://github.com/alexandrevicenzi/Flex themes/flex
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I'm unsure if this did both the work of formally adding the
submodule to the project (i.e. creating/modifying the &lt;code&gt;.gitmodules&lt;/code&gt;
file) &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; checking out the contents the submodule, but it may be the
case when a new submodule is added that you still need to initiate the
process of cloning/checking out the repo. You can do this with the
following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;git submodule update --init themes/flex
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;With that command the entire contents of the &lt;a href="https://github.com/alexandrevicenzi/Flex"&gt;Flex&lt;/a&gt; repo should
be in the local directory &lt;code&gt;themes/flex&lt;/code&gt;, which means I can now add the
theme to my Pelican configuration &lt;code&gt;pelicanconf.py&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;THEME = &amp;#39;themes/flex&amp;#39;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The theme is straightforward enough, but not as documented as it could
be, and I'm having to figure out some details by looking at the
&lt;a href="https://github.com/alexandrevicenzi/Flex/blob/master/tests/pelicanconf.py"&gt;test configuration&lt;/a&gt;. For example, it turns out you need
to explicitly enable &amp;amp; configure the menu menu at the top of the page;
it doesn't just list whatever 'pages' you have on your site:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;MAIN_MENU = True
MENUITEMS = (
    (&amp;#39;Archives&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;/archives.html&amp;#39;),
    (&amp;#39;Categories&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;/categories.html&amp;#39;),
    (&amp;#39;Tags&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;/tags.html&amp;#39;),
)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Additionally—and I'm not sure if this is specific to the Flex theme or
how you configure it for Pelican sites in general—I found that the
Favicon could be configured by setting the &lt;code&gt;FAVICON&lt;/code&gt; variable in my
configuration, like so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;PATH = &amp;#39;content&amp;#39;
STATIC_PATHS = [&amp;#39;images&amp;#39;]
FAVICON = &amp;#39;/images/favicon-red.ico&amp;#39;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;In this case &lt;code&gt;images/&lt;/code&gt; is a subdirectory of my &lt;code&gt;content/&lt;/code&gt; folder, which
is where I put all of my site content, and futhermore I specify that
&lt;code&gt;images&lt;/code&gt; is one of my &lt;code&gt;STATIC_PATHS&lt;/code&gt;, which I believe means the contents
of &lt;code&gt;images&lt;/code&gt; will be included in the generated site output irrespective of
whether Pelican finds any markdown posts in it to generate into articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm now going to try and get this site up on my Github pages, which means
if you're reading this you can expect an update shortly on how I did
that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="code"></category><category term="python"></category><category term="personal projects"></category></entry></feed>