<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Tetrahedrons &amp; Terminals - links</title><link href="http://dwgill.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://dwgill.com/feeds/links.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://dwgill.com/</id><updated>2017-07-10T10:15:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Aeon: Of Money and Morals</title><link href="http://dwgill.com/posts/2017/07/10/link-aeon-of-money-and-morals-alex-mayyasi/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-07-10T10:15:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-10T10:15:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Gill</name></author><id>tag:dwgill.com,2017-07-10:/posts/2017/07/10/link-aeon-of-money-and-morals-alex-mayyasi/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;An interesting article on the history of the ethics of moneylending&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://aeon.co/essays/how-did-usury-stop-being-a-sin-and-become-respectable-finance"&gt;Aeon recently published an fascinating essay on the history of ethical thought
around moneylending&lt;/a&gt;, particularly the practice of
&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Usury"&gt;&lt;em&gt;usury&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or lending money with interest. The primary contention
of the article is that ethical philosophers and theologians used to extensively
consider and write on the ethics of business and finance, but that's largely
left to economists, who since the 20th century have largely forgone conducting
ethical assessments in lieue of becoming scientists of economic phenomena.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until the rise of neoclassical economics in the 20th century that
economics became the supposedly scientific study of self-interest and individual
incentives – a domain in which economists do not pass judgment on actors in the
market, any more than biologists would judge the ‘morality’ of bees, or
engineers the ‘ethics’ of an aqueduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex Mayyasi would like the moral philosophers and theologians to once again
consider at length the ethical questions surrounding individual financial
arrangements and economic phenomena. It's a very interesting idea, and I recommend
the essay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's also so interesting to me, however, is just how much of a gap there seems
to be between a modern conception of interest-laden loans and what seems to have
been a nearly-universal condemnation of the practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In de Vitry’s world, the moneylender deserved to be defiled by demons, because
he’d committed the sin of usury – charging interest on a loan. De Vitry didn’t
care whether the rate was high or low, because the Church’s position was that
extracting a single cent of interest was evil. The roots of this revulsion
run deep, and across cultures. Vedic law in Ancient India condemned usury, and
rulers routinely capped interest rates from Ancient Mesopotamia to Ancient Greece.
In &lt;em&gt;Politics&lt;/em&gt;, Aristotle described usury as ‘the birth of money from money’, and
claimed it was unnatural because money was sterile and should not ‘breed’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judeo-Christian religions cemented the usury taboo. The Old Testament reads:
‘Do not charge a fellow Israelite interest,’ and the Book of Luke advises:
‘[L]ove ye your enemies: do good, and lend, hoping for nothing thereby.’ In
the 4th century CE, Christian councils denounced the practice, and by 800,
the emperor Charlemagne made the prohibition into law. Accounts of merchants
and bankers in the Middle Ages frequently include expressions of anguish over
their profits. In his Divine Comedy of the 14th century, the Italian poet
Dante Alighieri put the usurers in the seventh circle of Hell; in the case of
Reginaldo Scrovegni, one Paduan banker singled out by Dante, his son ended up
commissioning a chapel painted with frescoes by Giotto to expiate the
family’s sin. Over the ensuing centuries, the philanthropy and patronage of
other Italian Renaissance families such as the Medicis was partly inspired by
guilt about how they’d profited from charging interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that until at least the reformation, offering a loan with interest
was inconceivable as anything but inherently exploitative. An interesting
example of how much moral values have shifted over time, and a reminder that
ethical considerations have as much to do with the meaning and values we
ascribe to the things under consideration as they do with anything else.
Think of Aristotle's conception of money as "sterile," and how the sum-total
of his condemnation of interest stems from it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="link"></category><category term="aeon"></category><category term="alex mayyasi"></category><category term="philosophy"></category><category term="economics"></category><category term="history"></category><category term="ethics"></category></entry></feed>