<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Tetrahedrons &amp; Terminals - rpg</title><link href="http://dwgill.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://dwgill.com/feeds/rpg.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://dwgill.com/</id><updated>2017-04-22T10:46:00-04:00</updated><entry><title>Keeping Notes on Secret Doors</title><link href="http://dwgill.com/posts/2017/04/22/keeping-notes-on-secret-doors/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-22T10:46:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-04-22T10:46:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Daniel Gill</name></author><id>tag:dwgill.com,2017-04-22:/posts/2017/04/22/keeping-notes-on-secret-doors/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Some notes on documenting secret doors in Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I started semi-regularly running games of Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons recently,
and I've since been devouring all the advice on it I can read. I'm
particularly fond of the &lt;a href="https://media.wizards.com/2017/dnd/downloads/0227_UATraps.pdf"&gt;Unearthed Arcana on the subject&lt;/a&gt;
that Wizards of the Coast released a few months back, and appreciated
the structure suggested therein in articulating a trap: &lt;em&gt;Level and
Threat&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Trigger&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Effect&lt;/em&gt;. I've found this very useful in
guiding my thinking, and thought something similar might be useful in
describing secret doors and passages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Tentative Format for Describing Secret Doors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tentative elements I've come up with are the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Concealment:&lt;/em&gt; A description of the door/mechanism and how it is
  obscured from immediate detection or otherwise obstructs wanderers
  from opening it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trigger:&lt;/em&gt; Detail of how the door/mechanism is opened/operated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discovery:&lt;/em&gt; Example means by which characters might discover
  the secret door and determine how to open it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Destination:&lt;/em&gt; What opening the secret door uncovers and/or where the
  hidden passage leads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Example Secret Doors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm currently building a dungeon set in an ancient, abandoned Dwarven
mine, so I'll share the two secret doors I've come up with for that
project here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Drarven Statue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Concealment:&lt;/em&gt; A statue of a stately dwarf stands in the corner of a
  fork in the dungeon, extending an arm that raises an axe above his
  head.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trigger:&lt;/em&gt; Pull the arm down like a lever. It ratchets with a winding
  sound until it reaches the bottom of its arc, then the statue pulls 
  backward like a door on a hinge while the arm raises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discovery:&lt;/em&gt; A DC 15 Wisdom (Perception) check of the statue reveals
  seams around the base of the arm. A DC 15 Investigation check of
  the corner in general reveals a hallow sound to the walls about
  the corner, suggesting there is space in the interior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Destination:&lt;/em&gt; Opens into a cramped passage that leads directly to a
  hidden room full of treasure where a mimic lies in wait.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Banquet Hall Mosaic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Concealment:&lt;/em&gt; An elaborate 20 ft. mosaic that decorates a large
  banquet hall in the west end of the dungeon, depicting a great battle
  between the founders of the mine and hostile invaders, and obscuring
  a secret door embedded in the wall itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Trigger:&lt;/em&gt; Press in the eyes of the central heroic dwarf, and the door
  will unhook from the wall on one side and drift slightly forward on a
  hinge, eventually revealing a 5' wide opening if pulled the rest of
  the way. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Discovery:&lt;/em&gt; A DC 18 Wisdom (Perception) check reveals the fine seams
  that outline the door. A DC 15 Intelligence (Investigation) check
  determines that the aforementioned eyes of the hero of the mosaic have
  a polished or worn quality to them, indicative of how more frequently
  they were touched compared to the rest of the mosaic. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Destination:&lt;/em&gt; The door opens into a passageway that goes down to
  the second floor of the dungeon, leading to hidden cells where secret
  prisoners were once kept.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not sure how practical it is to use this format for describing
secret doors in my notes in preparing for sessions. I'm still new to
dungeon mastering, and I'm not sure how verbose I'm ultimately going
to want my notes to be. Regardless, I think I'm finding it useful in
guiding my thinking in designing secret doors. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="rpg"></category><category term="d&amp;d"></category><category term="d&amp;d 5e"></category><category term="game mastering"></category><category term="secret doors"></category></entry></feed>